RESUME

SANDEEP V

Computer Engineer, Full Stack Developer

SUMMARY

Engineering graduate with 3 years' experience in Start-ups in ecommerce systems, services and web applications. Experience includes developing web applications with scalable architecture, Fast-Loading server-side rendered, mobile optimized and with best UI-UX designs using the latest programming technologies. Passionate in modern computing technologies, developing software for the web, Blockchain systems and also an avid contributor to opensource software projects.

<u>INFO</u>

Full Name	Sandeep Vattapparambil
Address	Sandram House, Veettikkuthu, Nilambur, Malappuram District, Kerala, INDIA 679329
Phone	+91 7293289047
Email	sandeepv68@gmail.com

SOCIAL

GitHub	https://github.com/SandeepVattapparambil
LinkedIn	https://in.linkedin.com/in/sandeep-vattapparambil-4129496b
Medium	https://medium.com/@sandeepv68
Twitter	@SandeepVTPRL

EDUCATION

2010 - 2014	B.Tech in Computer Science & Engineering from KMCT College of Engineering under Calicut University - Calicut, Kerala, INDIA. With emphasis on Data Structures, Programming Paradigms, Logic Design, Computer Architecture, Parallel Processing, Compiler Design, Algorithm Design Analysis, Web Programming, Java, C, Machine Learning, Theory of Computation etc.
2008 - 2010	+2 Bio – Maths – Little Flower English Higher Secondary School, Nilambur
1996 - 2008	School Education – Good Hope English Higher Secondary School, Nilambur

EXPERIENCE

2018 -	Back End Engineer – Nylnda Pvt LTD.
	Currently designated as Back-End Engineer at Nylnda Pvt Ltd, Bangalore. My
	job is to build and maintain micro-services using AWS Lambda, NodeJS and
	MongoDB on mLab to support and serve as the back-end for the NyInda
	Mobile App. Building and maintaining the complete infrastructure of the app,
	creating support systems, tools, plugins and libraries, migrating databases
	across multiple database instances and ensuring code quality, continuous

	delivery, continuous deployment and continuous integration are part of my
	daily development and operations tasks.
	Tech Stack: NodeJS, AWS Lambda, MongoDB on mLab, React Native
2017 2010	(Android).
2017-2018	Software Engineer (Front-End UI-UX)
	Shopalyst Technologies, Bangalore IN
	 Designed, developed and implemented customized shoppable ad campaigns for global brands like Loreal, Pureit, Lakme and other Unilever brands for global markets using technologies like HTML5, CSS, JavaScript and MVC based UI framework MarkoJS v2 (from eBay) and ExpressJs. The main emphasis was given for factors like Fast loading web pages on feature phones and mobile optimized pages using server-side rendering and streaming data, SEO, Page Speed, scalability etc. Bazaar for Web – The web version of Shopalyst's Bazaar Mobile App. An ecommerce portal which brings multiple shopping sites onto a single platform with onsite checkout. url:https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=com.bazaar.app&hl=en The main prototype was developed using HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript, jQuery, MarkoJS v4, SCSS, LassoJS and ExpressJs. Shopalyst SDK – Dev Team Member - The core ecommerce engine of shopalyst ecosystem which can be integrated into a wide range of websites and ecom sites. Contains Product listings, Product Description pages, Brand landing pages, Brand stores, etc. Fast loading server-side rendering, compatibility with feature phones, optimized web pages for SEO and mobile devices, responsiveness, minimum network data usage, component based architecture, asynchronous execution and streaming data rendering etc. Tech Stack: HTML5, CSS, SCSS, JavaScript, ES6, jQuery, MarkoJS v4, Lassojs, i18next, Express ls. Node LS. Pino logger and Shopalyst SDK API for data
	 i18next, ExpressJs, NodeJS, Pino logger and Shopalyst SDK API for data. Transactional Email development – Designed and developed responsive transactional email templates for Shopalyst Insights Project using Zurb Foundation Email Framework.
2014 - 2016	Co-Founder and Chief Technology Officer at CodeLarvae Technologies, Research Project Incubated at Technology Business Incubator, National Institute of Technology – Calicut, NIT Campus, Calicut, Kozhikode, INDIA.
	Developed a Highly Scalable Cloud based Ecommerce Software-as-a-Service platform based on the latest cutting edge technologies and programming systems
	niattorm pased on the latest clitting edge technologies and programming systems
	available. The system was developed, keeping in mind the emerging demand for
	available. The system was developed, keeping in mind the emerging demand for ecommerce market in India and the demand for the best UI-UX for the customers.
	available. The system was developed, keeping in mind the emerging demand for ecommerce market in India and the demand for the best UI-UX for the customers. It was architected for the AWS cloud platform.
	available. The system was developed, keeping in mind the emerging demand for ecommerce market in India and the demand for the best UI-UX for the customers. It was architected for the AWS cloud platform. Technology Stack: HTML5, CSS3, JS, jQuery, NodeJS, ExpressJS, MySQL, MongoDB,
Feb 2013	available. The system was developed, keeping in mind the emerging demand for ecommerce market in India and the demand for the best UI-UX for the customers. It was architected for the AWS cloud platform.

ACHIEVEMENTS

Google India Challenge Scholarship: Front-End Web Dev from Google & Udacity

Official Contributor to Ebay Opensource – MarkoJS (UI Framework) - https://github.com/marko-js/marko/graphs/contributors

Blocktron Blockchain: Creator and maintainer of the project - https://github.com/Blocktron-Project

Opensource Npm Packages: Successfully published and maintaining 3 opensource projects on

npmjs.com

Link available below

SKILLS

Languages	English, Malayalam
Operating System	Windows, Linux, Mac
Programming Languages	HTML5, CSS, JavaScript, jQuery, NodeJS, ExpressJS, MarkoJS v2 & v4, ReactJS, C, Java, Python, PHP.
Database Management Systems	MySQL, MongoDB, Neo4J.
Programming Skills	Object Oriented Programming, Object Based Programming, ServerLess Architecture, Functional Programming, Software Architecture, REST, Cloud Architecture, Cloud Computing, Scalable and Distributed Software Systems, Software Version Control Systems, User Interface & User Experience Design (Front-End), Asynchronous Programming, Progressive Web Apps (PWA), Offline Web Apps, Responsive and Fluid Material Design for Front-End, BigData, SEO, Social Media Optimization, Web Analytics.
Software Package Management	Npm (Node.JS), Bower, Composer (PHP).
Software Frameworks & SDK	Bootstrap, MaterializeCSS (Google Material Design), Phonegap, MarkoJS
Development Workflow & Version Control	Git, GitHub
Cloud and Server Virtualization	Amazon Web Services (AWS), Heroku, Google App Engine
Software	WordPress, Adobe Dreamweaver CC, Adobe Photoshop CC, Adobe Acrobat Pro, Microsoft Office, Eclipse, NetBeans, Jet Brains, Atom
OpenSource Projects	WrapSplashJS – A NodeJS wrapper module to interact with Unsplash API https://www.npmjs.com/package/wrapsplash Express Marko Generator - A CLI tool to generate an Expressjs application with MarkoJS and MaterializeCSS framework https://www.npmjs.com/package/express-marko-generator blocktron-lib - A simple blockchain data structure library https://www.npmjs.com/package/blocktron-lib Blocktron - Blocktron is a simple yet elegant and efficient blockchain framework written in Javascript for Node.js environment. [WIP] https://github.com/Blocktron-Project
Hobby Projects	https://pwa-example-sandeep.herokuapp.com A Progressive Web App demo .

^{*}Any programming language or technology can be updated within a short notice.